<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Mobile Development - Tag - Tianyao Chen</title>
        <link>https://tillchen.com/tags/Mobile-Development/</link>
        <description>Mobile Development - Tag - Tianyao Chen</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>tillchen417@gmail.com (Tianyao Chen)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>tillchen417@gmail.com (Tianyao Chen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 21:49:50 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tillchen.com/tags/Mobile-Development/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Flutter Notes</title>
    <link>https://tillchen.com/posts/2020-06-16-Flutter-Notes/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 21:49:50 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://tillchen.com/posts/2020-06-16-Flutter-Notes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Declarative UI  Why How   Views  The equivalent of a view in Flutter How to update widgets   Intents  The equivalent of an Intent in Flutter How to handle incoming intents from external apps The equivalent of startActivityForResult()   Project structure and resources  Image files Strings   Layouts  Equivalent of a LinearLayout Equivalent of a RelativeLayout Equivalent of a ScrollView   Gesture detection and touch event handling  Equivalent of onClick Other gestures   ListView and adapters  Equivalent of ListView Which item is clicked   References  Introduction This post is assuming that the reader has Android development background.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>iOS Development Notes</title>
    <link>https://tillchen.com/posts/2019-08-13-iOS-Development-Notes/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://tillchen.com/posts/2019-08-13-iOS-Development-Notes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Basics View Controller Lifecycle: MVC Architecture Project Organization References  Basics   Model-View-Controller is a design pattern in iOS.
  Unlike in Android Studio, the Interface Builder is not a graphical representation of code. A storyboard file is an archive of object instances.
  Outlets are references to objects: @IBOutlet var questionLabel: UILabel! (IB means interface builder.) (Right click the item and drag it to the assistant editor to create the outlet.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Android Development Notes</title>
    <link>https://tillchen.com/posts/2019-07-10-Android-Development-Notes/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://tillchen.com/posts/2019-07-10-Android-Development-Notes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Table of Contents  Table of Contents Basics App Resources Permissions AndroidManifest.xml Layout Activities Fragments Notifications Android Studio Tips Miscellaneous Resources  Basics   Layout is typically defined in XML, whereas activities are in Java class.
  The Android operating system is a multi-user Linux system in which each app is a different user.
  App Resources   String array: android:entries=&quot;@array/foo&quot;.
1 2 3 4  &lt;string-array name=&#34;foo&#34;&gt; &lt;item&gt;bar1&lt;/item&gt; &lt;item&gt;bar2&lt;/item&gt; &lt;/string-array&gt;     Creating alias resources:]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
